#### KARTIK SHAH

kartik.isworking@gmail.com | +61 404 874 569

https://ikartiks.github.io/ | https://github.com/ikartiks | https://in.linkedin.com/in/ikartiks

### **Summary of Experience**

I have 6.3 years of experience in various domains like Banking, digital marketing & healthcare. My core forte is Android, but I have worked on both frontend and backend using technologies like Angular JS, Spring & Hibernate. I have also worked on NoSql technologies like CouchDb which offers in built sync mechanism with conflict resolution. I provide end to end Omni channel experience to clients as per requirements. I like building products. Love to teach & learn. This is a std. single page resume, detailed available on website. Looking for an opportunity at Sydney, New South Wales, Australia ( State sponsored PR holder).

## **Education**

Bachelor of Engineering, Information Technology, Mumbai University, 2011

#### Certifications

Google & Udacity's Android Developer Nanodegree, Udacity's Self Driving Car Nanodegree (Ongoing)

#### **Technical Skills**

Strong: Android, Kotlin, Backbase, CouchDB, Building voice actions with Home

Knowledgeable: Angular JS, Spring, JPA, Hibernate, HTML, CSS, SQL, Oracle, Python, Machine Learning, core PHP

Methodology: Agile using Jira & Pivotal Tracker, SCRUM, Kanban boards.

Tools: Jenkins for Continues integration, Burp Suite for network security, J-meter for load testing, GIT for version control.

### **Work Experience**

## Jan 2019 - Present, Telstra via Luvo (contract). Sydney, Australia

• Working on Telstra's 24x7 app.

# OCT 2015 – OCT 2018, Tata Consultancy Services. IT Analyst, Mumbai

- Leading a team of 7 developers to build a Banking application (HDFC). App has 10M+ installs & 3.9 \* rating.
- Built a hybrid app using phonegap for Sony Picture Entertainment's Digital windows project.
- Built, developed websites (backend and frontend) for Sony Picture Entertainment's SmartR project, SOAR

## Mar 2015 - Oct 2015, Freestone InfoTech Pvt. Ltd. Developer, Mumbai

- Led & performed development & maintenance using server side using Spring, JPA, and Hibernate.
- Managed complete lifecycle of app Vee Smart Home (VSH).

## Mar 2014 - Nov 2014, Gray Matrix Developer, Mumbai

- Led the development 3 projects Team Tracker, Cakesanpp and Dr.Fixit.
- Team Tracker was a product that helped us gain many customers as company's first product.

## May 2013 - Mar 2014, Megasys India Developer, Mumbai

Built, developed & designed complete lifecycle of 'IMSafe' mobile app, which was appreciated across states and within the
media as well.

## Feb 2012 - May 2013, Experience Commerce Pvt. Ltd. Developer, Mumbai

• Built & developed apps for engaging brands like Britannia, IPL Team - Royal Challengers Bangalore, United Spirits Limited, Adlabs Imagica and Daily News Analysis (DNA) newspaper.

## **Major Projects**

iviajoi riojects		
HDFC Bank	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.snapwork.hdfc	Android, Backbase, Kotlin
GRE Flashcards &	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.kartik.grevocab	Android, Kotlin
Tests (My product)		
SPE – SmartR, Digital		Spring, Hibernate JPA,
Windows		AngularJS, Phonegap
EPMWare	http://epmware.com/	
Home Automation		Android, PHP
app		
Dr. Fixit	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.pidilite.drfixit	Hybrid app development
Team Tracker	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.graymatrix.teamtracker	Android, Couch database
ImSafe		Android
USL's RCB IPL Team	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.royalchallengers.android	Android, core JS, PHP
USL's Signature	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.usl.signatureselfies	Android, core JS, PHP
Selfies app		
Britania's iHealthU	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.ihealthu.program.challenge	Android, core JS, PHP
Adlabs Imagica	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.adlabs.themepark	Android, core JS, PHP
Castrol Cricket	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.castrolcricket.android	Android, core JS, PHP
EC Diwali cracker app	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.experiencecommerce.android	Android, core JS, PHP

## Awards & Leadership

- Best team award at TCS, Client appreciation across multiple projects.
- Complete sponsorship to Mobile developer summit held in Bangalore 2013.
- Complete sponsorship to Udacity & Google's Android Developer Nanodegree course.
- Complete sponsorship to Google's Android Career summit Bangalore 2016 for top 50 selected Android developers across India.
- Conducted multiple trainings in JAVA, Android & JavaScript at TCS, single training on Machine Learning.